

### **CONTACT**

- Bogura, Bangladesh
- abidshahriar7@gmail.com
- https://github.com/abid-shahriar
- https://linkedin.com/in/abidshahriar
- https://abidshahriar.me

#### **SKILLS**

- HTML | CSS | SCSS
- JavaScript | TypeScript
- ReactJS | NextJS
- Redux | ContextApi
- NodeJS | Express
- Mongoose | MongoDB
- Postgres | Prisma | Knex
- Git | Github
- DigitalOcean App platform | S3 | SES

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Bengali (Native)
- English (Professional working proficiency)
- Hindi (Limited working proficiency)

### **HOBBIES**

- Coding
- Travelling
- Cooking

# ABID SHAHRIAR

Full-Stack Web Developer

#### **SUMMARY**

Creative full stack JavaScript Developer with 3+ years of experience and have a passion for building responsive, interactive and secure web applications. I have a strong background in web development and have worked on a wide range of projects. I like learning new technologies and always try to keep myself updated with the latest technologies.

### **EDUCATION**

## Bogura Zilla School, Bogura

Secondary School Certificate(SSC) in Science

Feb 2008 - Feb 2016

# Govt. Azizul Haque College, Bogura

Higher Secondary Certificate(HSC) in Science

Feb 2016 - Feb 2018

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelancer

Feb 2019 - Oct 2020

In my early days, I did freelancing with some local clients. I used to make school/restaurant and small e-commerce websites for them. After that I started freelancing with some remote clients. Gained a bunch of new skills doing these.

# Frontend Engineer

Wikiance | Nov 2020 - Sep 2021

https://wikiance.com

I mostly worked on their flagship product called Techiio. I was the lead developer on that project. My responsibilities were implementing api by coordinating with backend developers, adding new features, testing, scaling up, bug fixing, training interns etc. Learned a lot about teamwork, communication, best practices, and how to work in a fast-paced environment from here.

# Backend Engineer

Valkyrie IT LTD | Nov 2021 - Present

https://www.valkyrie-it.com/deck

As a backend engineer, my job here is creating secure and scalable backend, doing research and communicating with the frontend devs to make a website/app alive.